Second Dish
Episode 10
You don't look very happy, Eizan-kun.
（一色慧(いっしきさとし)）どこか浮かない顔だね
叡山君
What are you talking about?
（叡山(えいざん)枝津也(えつや)）何 言ってんだ
会場は大いに盛り上がってて―
The arena's really pumped.
This year's Autumn Selection is a major success.
今年の選抜は大成功
As the organizers,
we have nothing to be unhappy about.
運営として
これ以上の喜びはないだろう？
But it looks very different from how you imagined it to be, doesn't it?
しかし
君が実現させたかった風景とは―
だいぶ違うんじゃないのかな
Hmph.
フッ　何を言ってるのか
分からねえな
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
You're the one who directed Mimasaka Subaru
to target Souma-kun, aren't you?
創真君に美作昴(みまさかすばる)を
けしかけたのは―
君だろ
If he crushed Takumi-kun,
タクミ君を利用すれば
創真君は必ず勝負に乗ってくる
Souma-kun would no doubt agree
to the Cooking Battle.
If he were defeated before such a large crowd without being able to avenge his friend,
大衆の眼前で彼が友の無念を
晴らせず敗北したなら―
there would be no greater humiliation.
これ以上の屈辱はない
You kept your hands clean and manipulated everything from behind the scenes.
自分の手は汚さず
全てを裏から仕組んだ
It's very much your style, Eizan-kun.
とっても君らしいよ　叡山君
However, your schemes didn't work.
でも その目論見は外れたね
策を弄(ろう)して彼を
からめとろうとしたんだろうが―
You used your wits to set up a trap
the best you knew how,
but maybe you're the one who got caught and drowned instead.
創真君に巻き込まれ
のまれたのは―
君のほうじゃないのかい？
What did you just say?!
何だと？
I'd like you to have seconds too.
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）おかわりも
食べてほしいんすけど―
Does no one want more?
まだ食べたい人
いないっすか？
（堂島銀(どうじまぎん)）ここまで… だな
It's the end of the line.
With this, we conclude the evaluation—
ただ今を持って
審査を終了と…
If it means you'd have seconds,
（創真）
おかわりして頂けるなら―
I'd like you to pour this
over the rice and dig in.
こいつを注いで食べてもらおうと
思ってんすけど
（薙切(なきり)仙左衛門(せんざえもん)）むう！
（薙切(なきり)レオノーラ）はっ…
（堂島）うっ…
（葉山(はやま)アキラ）あっ…
（黒木場(くろきば)リョウ）ええっ
Well, to be more precise,
（一色）いや…
厳密に言えば
君だけじゃないのかもしれない
it wasn't only you.
Everyone at Tohtsuki
probably felt the same way.
たぶん この遠月(とおつき)学園の全員が
そうだったんだ
（叡山）んっ…
My Pacific saury dish is not yet complete.
俺のサンマ料理は
まだ完成してないんすよ
That's...
（薙切(なきり)えりな）それは…
a white soup?
白いスープ
♪～
omoiegaiteru imeeji yori haruka mukou gawa e
Far beyond the image I have in my mind
tsukuriagete yuku shinjitsu wa mada tooku
The reality I'm building up is still far away
hatenai tabiji
An endless journey
otagai no puraido wo togisumaseyou ze
Let's hone each other's pride
kotoba nante kazari wa hadakesaserya ii
Make people see that words are cheap and unimportant
butsukariai migakarete iku
We fight each other and hone our skills
Rolling stone
deai wa shockwave shockwave
Our encounters cause shockwaves
mada shiranai sekai e
We're reckless challengers
arukihajimeta mubou na chousensha sa
Heading toward a world as yet unexplored
te ni shita yaiba de ashita wo
With the blade in your hand
kirihirakeba iin darou
Open the way to the future
dareka no mon ja nai jibun dake no story
This is my story and no one else's
Cause we're still rough diamonds on the road
～♪
A NEW GENIUS
（仙左衛門）おかわりを頂こう
Let's have seconds.
フッ
Yukihira-kun, you're free to
struggle on till the very end,
（薙切(なきり)アリス）幸平君
最後の悪あがきは結構だけれど
これでは―
but isn't this just a remake of the idea you used in your match against me?!
私と対決した時のアイデアを―
焼き直したに
過ぎないのではなくて？
No, it's not, Alice.
（えりな）いいえ　違うわ アリス
It's—
これは…
There, honored judges.
（創真）さあ お三方
これが俺のサンマ料理
This is my Pacific saury dish:
Porridge-Style Pacific Saury Rice.
“サンマの炊き込みご飯
おじや風”
Enjoy!
おあがりよ！
The slightly viscous soup
（堂島）
わずかに とろみのかかった
このスープが―
has soaked into the dish
炊き込みご飯に溶け込み
ご飯と柔らかくなじんでいる
and gently melded with the rice.
（飲み込む音）
There he goes!
（男子生徒Ａ）
いった～　おはだけ～！
Bare-chested!
Mild and creamy...
まろやかでクリーミー
This white soup is soy milk!
この白いスープの正体は―
豆乳だ
That's right.
（創真）そのとおり
I gradually added miso and just a touch of Parmesan cheese to the soy milk,
こいつは豆乳に みそと
パルミジャーノ･チーズを―
ちょっぴりずつ加えて コトコト
じっくり温めたものなんす
then slowly simmered it
until the soup became warm.
Soy milk?
豆乳ですって？
ハッ
You noticed, Alice.
気付いたようね アリス
The critical component of porridge is the broth.
おじやの肝は何と言ってもだし
He used soy milk as the broth and built his dish on that foundation.
彼は豆乳をだしとして位置付け
この料理を構築したのよ
I see.
そういうこと
Broth is essentially umami itself.
（アリス）だしとは要は
旨味そのもののこと
Like kelp, soy milk contains
large quantities of glutamic acid.
豆乳は昆布と同じグルタミン酸を
たっぷり含んでいる
It's more than qualified to serve as the base for the porridge's flavor.
十分に おじやのおいしさの
ベースを担うことができるんだわ
Further, umami components
have a synergistic effect.
（えりな）さらに旨味には
相乗作用があり―
When two are present, the resultant umami
is far more than the sum of its parts.
２つの成分が共存すると
はるかに強いおいしさになる
The inosinic acid from Pacific saury
サンマのイノシン酸と
豆乳のグルタミン酸
and the glutamic acid from soy milk...
Combining the two makes total sense.
これらを合わせるのは
理に適っている
A soy milk porridge.
豆乳のおじや
How interesting.
いと面白し
There are ingredients that have suddenly become prominent by adding the soup, as well.
（堂島）さらにスープを
加えたことで―
がぜん存在感を
放ち始めた素材もある
What's mixed into the rice?
ご飯に混ぜ込まれていた これは？
Crunchy pickled plums.
カリカリ梅っす
What?!
（男子生徒Ｂ）ええっ？
（女子生徒Ａ）カリカリ梅？
Crunchy pickled plums?
What?!
（青木(あおき)大吾(だいご)）何ぃっ？
Not common snacks again?!
（佐藤昭二(さとうしょうじ)）
また駄菓子シリーズかよ
These plums serve as important accents.
この梅が また重要なポイントに
なっています
The crunchy mouthfeel is fun,
adding vivid visual impact!
カリコリと楽しい食感と
見た目の鮮やかさ
For the taste buds, the plums help cut through the fattiness of the Pacific saury and provide a refreshing aftertaste.
味覚の点でもサンマの豊富な脂を
すーっと断ち―
さわやかな後味をもたらしています
The dish makes full use of the acidity's ability to increase appetite.
酸味が持つ食欲増進作用も
フルに活用していますね
The plums were pickled in salt.
そして梅もまた
塩漬けによって作られるもの
They are the perfect choice
to complement the aged Pacific saury!
熟成サンマを彩るのに
ピッタリですわ
Another item of note
is the Parmesan cheese in the soup.
さらに特筆すべきは―
スープに入っている
パルミジャーノ･チーズ
This Western ingredient is combined with Japanese ingredients,
この西洋の素材と
糠サンマ 梅 みそなどの―
such as the salted rice-bran Pacific saury,
pickled plums, and miso,
和の食材が組み合わさって
新しいおいしさを作り出しています
to create a brand new flavor!
It reminds me of when I met my beloved.
（レオノーラ）
思い出します
愛しい あの人と
知り合った頃のこと…
ウフフフ　こっちですよ
This way.
あっ
An encounter made possible by two
that have developed
（レオノーラ）
違う国 違う文化で
育った２人が―
in different countries and cultures.
手を取り合うことで生まれる
唯一無二の出会い
A most unique encounter.
ウフフ
You've got to be kidding.
（男子生徒Ｃ）ウソだろ
That's high praise right there.
（男子生徒Ｄ）
すげえ高評価じゃねえか
Who knew that the transfer student would...
（男子生徒Ｅ）
まさか あの編入生が？
（叡山）ん…　あっ
（一色）叡山君は見たかな？
Did you see this Tohtsuki Spotlight issue?
この遠スポ
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
According to the journalism club,
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
新聞部によれば
創真君をたたく記事を載せると―
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
they can sell more copies when they write an article bashing Souma-kun.
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
部数が伸びるそうだよ
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
News Flash
Tohtsuki
Spotlight
Autumn
Election Finals
Of course they would.
当然だな
He publicly said that this academy's just a stepping stone for him.
何しろ この学園を踏み台だと
言い切った男だ
You can tell from the audience's reaction too.
会場の反応を見ても分かる
They dislike him not just from afar
but in person as well.
名実共に嫌われ者の編入生だ
Is that really true?
（一色）そうかな
I don't think that's the only reason.
僕にはどうしても
それだけとは思えないんだ
He had a very close spice match with Hayama-kun in the prelims.
予選では葉山君と
スパイス対決で接戦を演じ―
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
Hayama Akira
Yukihira Souma
Kurokiba Ryou
In the main tournament, he defeated Alice-kun,
a relative of the Devil of Food.
本選では食の魔王の眷属(けんぞく)である
アリス君を倒し―
Furthermore, he overcame Mimasaka-kun, a monster who'd been undefeated in 99 Cooking Battles.
さらに食戟(しょくげき)99戦無敗の怪物
美作君を下した
Yet many students don't want
to acknowledge Souma-kun.
なのに 多くの生徒が
創真君を認めたくない
Why is that?
それは なぜか？
Souma-kun's father
told me something once.
僕は創真君のお父上に
聞いたことがあるんだ
Sumire
Street
Yukihira Diner
Sumire
Street
Dad!
Sumire
Street
（創真）親父！
Sumire
Street
I'm gonna become a chef
who can beat you, Dad!
俺な 親父に勝てる料理人になる！
Oh, yeah?
（幸平城一郎(ゆきひらじょういちろう)）おお そうか
Well, good luck.
まっ 頑張れや
Okay!
じゃあ 早速…
Let's do a cooking match right now!
料理勝負だ！
In my eyes, Souma didn't have
any special cooking skill.
（城一郎）俺から見て創真は―
特別 料理の才能が
あったわけじゃなかった
Kids say that sort of thing,
子供の言うことだし―
so I thought he'd have enough once I beat him a couple of times.
何回か負かしてやれば
気が済むだろうって思ってたんだ
But Souma never let himself get down.
だが―
創真は一度たりとも へこたれない
Every time, he gets one step closer.
着実に一歩ずつ近付いてくる
One day, I realized something.
ある日 気付いたんだ
Souma lacks something any
normal person would have.
普通の人間なら
当然 持ってるものが―
創真には欠落してるんだってな
And what is that?
と 言いますと？
See, everyone wants to believe
みんな 思いたいんだよ
that it's normal to do worse
than someone who has talent.
才能ある奴に負けても
しょうがない… ってな
That way, they lower their expectations
そうやって人は心に
ふたをしちまう
and protect their pride, self-respect, and similar sorts of things.
プライドとか自尊心
そういったもんを守りたいからだ
But Souma doesn't do that.
だが創真には そのふたがない
He has the strength
to face his inadequacies head-on.
自分の足りない部分に
あっけらかんと向き合う強さ
That's an incredible strength
that even I don't have.
それは俺にもなかった
とんでもねえ強みなんだ
Souma-kun's cooking inspirations
（一色）創真君の料理の閃(ひらめ)き
aren't from natural genius
or anything like that.
それをもたらすのは
天性の才能でも何でもなく―
He just thinks things through.
ただ考え抜く
試行錯誤を続け抜くことだ
He keeps testing and retesting his recipes.
Everyone can do that,
but not everyone actually does.
それは誰にだってできることだが
実はそうではない
I bet it won't work.
（男子生徒Ｆ）
やっぱり無理なんだろうな
He's up against Hayama Akira,
who has a superhuman sense of smell.
（男子生徒Ｇ）相手は嗅覚(きゅうかく)の超人
葉山アキラだぜ
Kurokiba Ryou is an elite who was
handpicked by the Nakiri family too.
（男子生徒Ｈ）黒木場リョウも
薙切家に選ばれたエリートだし
A way to beat them?
（男子生徒Ｉ）勝つ方法？
そんなの考えようとも思わねえ
I wouldn't even bother thinking one up.
（女子生徒Ｂ）絶対 無理だもん
It's impossible.
Of course the genius will win.
（男子生徒Ｊ）
天才が勝つのは当たり前だからな
Why did they want to
think less of Souma-kun?
（一色）彼らがなぜ
創真君を低く見たがったのか？
Because if they acknowledged him,
創真君を認めれば―
it'd mean acknowledging
their own lack of effort.
努力していない自分を
認めることになるからさ
あっ…
（叡山）んっ…
But the tide's about to turn.
でも その潮目は
今 変わりつつある
He's amazing!
（男子生徒Ｋ）すげえな
（男子生徒Ｌ）うん
Yeah.
He's playing against those
two monsters at their level!
（男子生徒Ｍ）
対等に渡り合ってるぞ
あの化け物２人に
（男子生徒Ｎ）
あいつ 届くかもしれない
He might be able to do this.
After this, I can't help but acknowledge him.
（男子生徒Ｏ）
ああ こんなの認めるしかねえよ
Yukihira...
（男子生徒Ｐ）幸平
（男子生徒Ｑ）幸平
Yukihira.
Yukihira!
（女子生徒Ｃ）幸平
（男子生徒Ｒ）幸平
Yukihira.
Yukihira Souma is...
（男子生徒Ｓ）幸平創真って…
（学生たち）すげえ！
...amazing!
Glad you liked it!
御粗末！
（仙左衛門）これにて審査は終了
With this, we conclude the evaluation!
And now, the verdict!
判定である！
（観客の歓声）
Oh, c'mon.
（吉野(よしの)悠姫(ゆうき)）
もう～　どうなの？　どうなの？
Well? What is it?
I'm sure it'll be okay!
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）大丈夫よ きっと
He can do it!
（水戸(みと)郁魅(いくみ)）行ける！　行けるぜ
He can!
Souma-kun...
（田所(たどころめぐみ)恵）創真君…
Yukihira...
（黒木場）
幸平… 目利きの差を埋めた上で
ここまでの品を
After closing the gap in ingredient quality,
you even managed to make a dish of that caliber.
Interesting.
（葉山）面白(おもしれ)えよ
本当に面白えよ 幸平
You're really interesting, Yukihira.
ふう…
Good or bad, this is the final result.
（創真）
泣いても笑っても これでお開き
This is it!
（黒木場･創真･葉山）決着だ
First, well done.
まずは ご苦労であった
Each of you presented your unique strengths well,
決勝を戦うに値する個性の
ぶつかりあい
in a clash befitting the grand finale.
三者三様の持ち味を見せてもらった
First, regarding your cooking techniques,
まず調理の技術
これは全員 伯仲している
all three of you are on par.
Next, regarding your ability
to judge ingredient quality,
次に素材の目利きについては―
Kurokiba and Hayama are clearly exceptional.
何と言っても黒木場と葉山だ
They made the perfect choices
when selecting their Pacific saury.
最上のサンマを
完璧に選び抜いてみせた
However, Yukihira has closed the gap
through his creativity.
だが 幸平はその創意工夫で
見事 追いついた
His inventiveness is exceptional among the three!
発想力は３名の中で群を抜いている
（観客のどよめき）
（恵）ああっ
（郁魅）よし！
Great!
Even more surprisingly,
（仙左衛門）
さらに驚くべきことに―
all three dishes had flavors that were nearly equal.
味についても３名共に
ほぼ互角と言えるうまさであった
（観客のどよめき）
However, the deciding factor
而(しか)して
勝負の決め手となったのは―
was how well the dish reflected
the chef as an individual.
料理人の顔が見える料理かどうか
な… 料理人の顔… っすか
The chef as an individual?
That's right, Yukihira-kun.
（レオノーラ）
そのとおりです 幸平君
A dish brimming with true originality
本当のオリジナリティーに
あふれた皿は味わっただけで―
allows you to picture the chef in your mind just by tasting the dish.
その料理人の顔が心に
浮かんでくるものですから
Put differently,
言い換えるなら―
it's a dish with such originality
その者にしか作ることのできない
真に独創性のある一皿
that only one specific chef could've created it.
As a sign of respect, we call
such a dish the chef's specialty.
そんな料理のことを我々は―
作った者への敬意を込めて―
“必殺料理(スペシャリテ)”と呼ぶのだ
The one who deserves victory
頂点に立つべきは己の料理を
最も深く追求した料理人
is the chef who best pursued his own cooking!
The chef who truly sought what his cooking should look like!
己の料理とは何かという問いに
真に向き合った者だ
And that person's name is...
その人物の名は…
（心臓の鼓動）
8 YEARS AGO
（葉山）
親の顔も自分の名前も知らない
I don't know what my parents look like or what my real name is.
All I know
分かっているのは
スラム街の外れに赤ん坊の頃―
is that I was abandoned as a newborn in the outskirts of the slum.
捨てられていたということだけ
You deserve better than this.
（汐見潤(しおみじゅん)）君にふさわしい場所は
そこじゃないよ
Your sense of smell may remake the world itself!
君の嗅覚は
世界を変えちゃうかもしれない
It was Shiomi Jun who pulled me out of the slums.
（葉山）
汐見潤という女によって―
俺はスラム街から引っ張り出された
Professor Hayama,
who was Jun's advisor at the time,
当時 潤が師事していた
葉山教授が―
agreed to become my legal guardian.
身元引受人になってくれた
Raising a Child for
.the First Time
“新しき料理の世界を
明らかにし照らす子に”
Raising a Child for
.the First Time
They chose my name to indicate
someone who would bring
Raising a Child for
.the First Time
a new world of cooking to light.
そんな意味を込めて
“アキラ”と名を付けられた
Hayama Akira
I was named Akira.
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Middle
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Jun was always by my side.
俺の隣には いつも潤がいた
Akira-kun is a very good boy.
（汐見）
アキラ君は とてもいい子です
He's so earnest in helping with my research.
熱心に研究を手伝ってくれて―
He helps compensate for what I lack.
私の足りない所を補ってくれます
I can't thank him enough, really.
本当に感謝しても し足りません
But...
でも…
怖いんです　私は自分のために―
I'm scared.
I'm scared that for my own sake,
アキラ君が望まぬことを
させてるんじゃないかって
I'm making Akira-kun do something he doesn't really want to do.
（汐見の泣き声）
No.
（葉山）違う
That's not true, Jun.
違うよ… 潤
You saw something in me... My true worth.
俺の価値を見いだしてくれた
（汐見）君にふさわしい場所は―
You deserve better than this.
そこじゃないよ
（葉山）俺に生きる意味をくれた
You gave me a reason to live!
You're the one who brought me into the light.
俺を照らしてくれたのは あなただ
I have to win for Jun.
勝たなきゃならない
潤のために
This isn't good enough!
（机をたたく音）
これじゃ まだダメだ
My cooking's meaningless
unless I can win using a method
誰にもマネできない方法で
勝たなけりゃ―
that no one else can copy.
俺が作る意味がない
I will change the world of taste through the power of fragrance.
香りの力で味の世界を変える
That's my cooking.
それが俺の料理なんだ
I'll give everything I have to offer to this one dish!
この一皿に俺の全てを捧げる
Victor
The 43rd Autumn Selection Main Tournament Grand Finale
The victor...
勝者！
is Hayama Akira!
葉山アキラ！
The 43rd Autumn Selection Main Tournament Grand Finale
Victor
Hayama Akira
（観客の歓声）
Hayama!
（男子生徒Ｔ）葉山だ
（男子生徒Ｕ）葉山だ～！
It's Hayama!
Seared Pacific Saury Carpaccio.
（仙左衛門）
炙(あぶ)りサンマのカルパッチョ
The dish was worthy of being called a specialty.
スペシャリテと呼ぶにふさわしい
一皿であった
（黒木場）くっ…　くう…
Congratulations, Hayama-kun!
（汐見）おめでとう 葉山君！
あ…
Congratulations.
おめでとう　おめで… ひっ
Congratu...
You did it, Hayama-kun!
うう… やったねえ 葉山君
ひっ よかった… よかったぁ ひっ
I'm so happy for you! So happy.
Ugh, you always keep your cool.
もう 相変わらずクールなんだから
もうちょっと喜びなよぉ
You should act a little happy!
ズズッ 優勝…
For winnin—
（汐見）あっ…
（観客のどよめき）
（汐見）えっ…
Huh?!
ええええ～っ！
あっ…
Akira-kun, wh-what's wrong?
はや… はや… アキラ君
ど どうしたにょ？
N-Nothing!
なっ… 何でもねえ
Akira-kun, the smell of cinnamon
is said to cheer you up.
アキラ君 シナモンの香りには
心を元気にする効果があるんだよ
I see.
（堂島）そうか　準決勝の時の顔
His expression during the semi-finals.
I'm the one who'll climb to the top!
（葉山）上へ行くのは俺だ
誰も近付けさせるか！
I won't let anyone else get close!
That wasn't a smile of confidence.
（堂島）あれは余裕の笑みなどでは
なかったのか
It was to rouse himself.
己を鼓舞するための
もはや威嚇(いかく)に近い形相
It was almost as though
he was threatening himself.
（堂島）危ういな
（レオノーラ）えっ？
How fragile.
What?
Hayama-kun, that was a wonderful dish.
（堂島）
葉山君 すばらしい料理だった
ありがとうございます
堂島シェフ
Thank you, Chef Doujima.
But too great a talent
だが 大きすぎる才は―
will turn against itself in the end.
やがて自らにも爪を立てる
（葉山）あ…
I hope that you will be able to maintain a good relationship with your talent.
君がその才能とうまく
付き合っていけるよう願っている
（汐見）ああ…
くう…
Ryou-kun!
リョウ君！
Jeez! Jeez, jeez, jeez, jeez, jeez!
もう！　もう もう もう もう
もう もうっ
I can't believe you lost right in front of me!
この私が見てる前で敗北するなんて
Jeez, jeez, jeez, jeez, jeez!
（アリス）もう もう もう もう
もう もう もう もうっ
Hey, that hurts.
（アリス）もう もう もう もう
もう もう もう もうっ
（黒木場）
痛(いて)えな コラァ
What's that for, bitch?!
（黒木場）何しやがんだ てめえは
（アリス）ま まあっ
Oh?!
How dare you call your master a bitch?
主(あるじ)に向かって“てめえ”だなんて
もう絶交よ！
We're through!
You can apologize to me once you feel sorry!
反省したら謝りに来なさい
がーっ！
I'm gonna become a chef who can beat you!
（創真）俺な
親父に勝てる料理人になる
Hm?
ん？　おい 創真
Hey, Souma.
That sardine is no good.
（城一郎）そのイワシはダメだぞ
（創真）えっ
Huh?
Don't lose to anyone else
before you lose to me next time.
（城一郎）次に俺に負けるまで
誰にも負けんじゃねえぜ
（創真のため息）
Hayama.
（創真）葉山
（葉山）ん？
Can you make more of that carpaccio?
あのカルパッチョ まだ作れるか？
I guess I still have the ingredients.
（葉山）食材は まだ一応…
（創真）食わせてくれ
Let me have a taste.
Huh?
ああ？
Why?
（葉山）なんでだよ
（創真）食わせて
Let me have some.
Uh, but it takes some work—
（葉山）いや…
つっても いろいろ手間が…
Let me try it too, bastard!
俺にも食わせやがれ コラァ！
Why're you acting like
you're trying to start a fight?
（葉山）
なんで お前はケンカ腰だよ
What's with you two?
（葉山）一体 何なんだ お前ら
（創真）う～ん
ケッ 俺なら
もっとうまく作れるぜ
I would've been able to make it better.
Huh? A sore loser, I see.
（葉山）あ？　負け惜しみかよ
（黒木場）んん…
Listen.
いいか 今夜で１年生の暫定序列が
組み上がった
Tonight decided the first-years'
preliminary rankings.
Among us here, I'm the top seat.
この中じゃ 俺が１番上なんだ
You should show me respect from now on.
これからは口の利き方を
考えたほうがいいぜ
Want to have a rematch right now?!
今から もう１回 勝負するか？
コラァ
Sure.
いいとも　どうせ結果は同じだ
The results still won't change.
Now, now.
（創真）まあ まあ
Hayama, you made a pretty good dish too.
葉山も なかなか いい品
作ったんじゃねえの
Why're you talking down to me, third place?
（葉山）
なんで お前も上から目線だ
この３位野郎！
You don't know that!
３位かどうか分かんないだろ
適当なこと言うな！
Don't make things up!
You're saying I ranked below you?!
俺が てめえより下だってのかぁ！
Don't yell while eating!
（葉山･創真）
食いながら叫ぶなっ！
（創真）でも葉山もよかったぞ
But yours was good too, Hayama.
Maybe there's nothing
to worry about with Hayama.
葉山に限っては
心配はないのかもしれないな
Those three look to become an interesting trio.
あの３人 なかなか面白いトリオに
なりそうじゃないか
（レオノーラ）フフ　そうですね
Right.
Diamonds in the rough collide,
polishing each other.
原石たちがぶつかり合い
磨き合う―
これこそ遠月の理念に
他ならないなのです
That's exactly what Tohtsuki is all about.
Indeed. Tonight, yet another
new gem has been created!
うむ　今宵 ここに―
新たな玉(ぎょく)がまた１つ生まれたのだ
（叡山）チッ
THE 43RD AUTUMN SELECTION (92ND CLASS)
VICTOR
HAYAMA AKIRA
Souma-kun, that was really good work!
創真君 本当にお疲れ様
Okay, tonight, we celebrate
Yukihira finishing second!
（悠姫）よ～し 今夜は幸平の
準優勝祝いだ　騒ぐぞぉ～！
Let's party!
Yeah, in Marui's room!
（青木）おう！ 丸井の部屋でな
（携帯電話の振動音）
Why is it always my room?
（丸井(まるい)善二(ぜんじ)）
なんで いつも僕の部屋なんだ
（携帯電話の振動音）
Because it's big, okay?
（佐藤）広いんだから いいだろ～
ゲッ
Crap!
Sorry, can you guys go ahead?
（創真）悪(わり)ぃ 先 行ってくれ
（恵）ああ…
（電話の呼び出し音）
What do you want, Dad?
（創真）何だよ 親父
Hey, Souma.
おう 創真　久しぶりだな
Been a while.
Well?
（城一郎）で 選抜本選は
どうだった？
How'd the main tournament go?
Oh, well.
（創真）
あ… ああ まあ うん その…
So...
Aw! You lost, huh?!
（城一郎）
うわ～　負けたのか お前
優勝は誰だよ？
Who won?
Hayama.
葉山
Oh, Shiomi's disciple, huh.
（城一郎）
ああ　汐見の弟子かぁ
ハッ　頼むぜ～　俺が汐見に
負けたみたいじゃねえかよ　ん～？
Get it together, yeah?
It's like I lost to Shiomi.
Shit.
（創真）クソッ　俺をからかう時
異様に生き生きしてやがる
（城一郎）
ヘッヘッヘ　アハハハ
He's so upbeat when he's making fun of me.
What kind of parent feels happy
when their son loses?
息子が負けて喜ぶとか なんて親だ
Well, but to be fair,
まあ でも ぶっちゃけ―
if you can perfect fragrance, it's amazing.
香りってのは極めりゃ
ものすげえからな
No, that wasn't all there was to it.
いや　それだけじゃなかった
In his dish...
あいつの皿の上には…
I sensed overwhelming tenacity.
（創真）執念みたいなものが
Dad, I'm glad I left Yukihira.
（創真）
親父　俺 ゆきひら出てよかった
If I hadn't, I wouldn't have
noticed all these things.
じゃなきゃ気付かなかった
いろんなことにさ
So, I'm going to explore
the kind of cooking only I can do.
んで これからは―
俺にしかできない料理って何なのか
そいつを探ってく
If I don't do that,
そうじゃないと―
there's no point in my carrying
on the family business.
俺が ゆきひらを継ぐ意味が
ないもんな　あれ？
Huh?
Now that I've said it,
こう言っちまうと 今までと
やること あんま変わんねえような
that doesn't sound that different
from what I've been doing already.
（城一郎）いや
Well...
Why not? Be that way.
いいんじゃねえの そんな感じで
（城一郎のあくび）
Was that a yawn?
（創真）あくびって お前…
Bye.
（城一郎）じゃあな
（創真）あ…
（電話の切れる音）
He's finally met someone his age
（城一郎）やっと同年代で―
who can blow who he is now
out of the water, huh?
今までの自分を吹っ飛ばしてくれる
相手に当たったか
That's right, Souma.
そうだ　創真よ
Meet them.
出会うことで―
Only through these encounters
can a chef move forward.
出会うことでしか
料理人は前に進めない
If you face a dish on your own,
たった１人で皿に向き合っても―
you'll only see the same self as before.
それまでと変わらない自分が
映るだけ
My own cooking, huh.
（創真）
俺の… 俺自身の料理か
♪～
seki wo kitta nodo kara te ga deru hodo
An intensely burning desire burst forth
hoshiku nattan da boku ja nai betsu no dareka
But not from me, from someone else
yume to kibou hoka ni nani ga iru to
Where's the me who believed that
omoeta koro no boku wa ima izuko e?
All one needs is to have hopes and dreams
nagai mono ni makarete ushinatta michishirube
Wrapped around something long, my compass was lost
sei to shi no hazama ni wa sunoo duroppu ga sakimidareru
On the border of life and death, snow drops bloom
nanika no machigai de kudakechitte shimatta nara
If by some mistake they get smashed
semete boku no nukegara ni hanataba wo soete
At least put flowers on the empty husk
konna mon ka na konna mon deshou
Is that the way things are? Yes, it is
akirame da to omowaretatte kamawanai kedo
You can call it resignation if you want
boku rashiku nai boku rashiku nai
But that's not me, that's not me
dare ni mo datte tsukureru mon ni kachi wa nai
There's no value in something just anyone could make
～♪
A FEW DAYS LATER
Hiya!
ちわーっす
Nikumi-cchi!
（悠姫）郁魅っち
（涼子）いらっしゃい
Welcome!
Thanks for the text.
（郁魅）メールありがとな
You got a shipment of good game meat?
ジビエの いいのが
入ったんだって？
Nice!
（悠姫）うん　うまそうだよぉ～
Looks tasty!
Here.
（恵）はい　私のだけど
似合ってるよ
It's one of mine, but it looks good on you!
Oh, thank you, Megumi.
うん　サンキュー 恵
All right, let's start!
よし　じゃあ始めよっか～
Yeah!
（郁魅･涼子･恵）
お～！
ハハ　ステキだね
How nice.
Lovely girls in a kitchen working together in harmony.
可憐な乙女たちが和気あいあいと
キッチンに立つ姿
It doesn't appear so lovely
when you actually look at it, though.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）見た目的には
可憐さとは程遠いけどな
（郁魅）
オラオラオラオラ～！
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）見た目的には
可憐さとは程遠いけどな
（悠姫）ふんぬ～！
By the way, where's Yukihira?
ところで幸平は？
Oh, he's back there today.
あっ　それが今日も…
So, the mellow soy milk flavor
（創真）ってわけで
豆乳のまろやかさが―
enhances the gentle saltiness of the Pacific saury in a good way.
サンマの優しい塩気をいい感じに
際立たせてくれるんだよなぁ
Still, crunchy pickled plums feel too cheap
にしても カリカリ梅は
安っぽい感じだ
for me to want to eat them.
食う気にならねえんだよな
But you're shoveling it in
like you like it!
ガツガツ食ってんじゃん
うまそうに
おかわり
Seconds.
And you want another serving?
…って ２杯目いくのかよ
The cartoccio I made for you
yesterday was better, though.
昨日 作ってやった俺の
カルトッチョのが うまいけどな
Huh?!
はあ～？　だったら
もう一度 作ってみやがれ！
Then try making it again!
Let's compare!
食べ比べだぁ！
Whatever, but why are you guys
taste-testing at our place?
どうでもいいけど なんで うちで
試食し合ってんだよ
I made tea!
お茶が入ったよ～
What?!
（葉山）な…　いいよ 潤
もてなさなくて
You don't have to play hostess, Jun.
And why're you offering such high-quality cookies?
しかも こんな高級クッキー
いいんだよ あいつらには
安もんの菓子で
They'll be fine with cheap snacks!
Hey, we can hear you.
聞こえてんぞ おい
You're a skinflint and a nagger too.
The specialty... a dish that shows the chef's character.
（黒木場）
みみっちいやつだな
口うるせーし
（創真）スペシャリテ
料理人の顔が見える一皿
That's because you're such a pig.
（創真）スペシャリテ
料理人の顔が見える一皿
（葉山）
お前が意地汚(きたね)えからだよ
What Hayama's cooking has, but mine lacks.
葉山の料理にあって
俺に足りないもの
（黒木場）ガ～
（葉山）なっ おい 流し込むな
Hey! Don't cram them all into your mouth!
Hayama!
葉山ぁ
I want to compare dishes.
ちょっと食べ比べたいからよ
One Seared Pacific Saury Carpaccio, thanks.
炙りサンマのカルパッチョを
よろしく
Make that two.
２人前
Shut up. Go home.
うるせえ　帰れ
Two on the double, yeah?
（創真･黒木場）大至急な
You guys!
（葉山）お前ら！
ウフッ
Yukihira's crazy,
（青木）
幸平のやつ 負けた相手のところに
入り浸るなんてよぉ
spending all that time with someone he lost to.
Yeah.
ああ
悔しくねえのかなぁ あいつ
Isn't he frustrated by the results?
I'm sure Souma-kun feels more frustrated than we'll ever know.
（一色）創真君は きっと
悔しくてたまらないんだと思うよ
That's why he's there all the time.
（一色）だから入り浸ってる
（青木･佐藤）あ…
But to know who you really are,
でも 己が何者かを
知るためには―
you must step outside the world you know.
自分の世界の外へ
踏み出すしか手はない
Even if that means facing the one who got the better of you.
たとえ 自分を負かした相手と
向き合うことになろうとも
I'm sure the same goes for the girls too.
きっと 彼女らも
そうなんだと思うよ
They're trying their best to learn
something from others,
相手から少しでも何かを
つかもうと もがいてる
just like Souma-kun.
創真君のように
Damn, we can't be left behind.
ええい 俺らも負けてらんねえな
Let's do a taste-testing festival!
（青木）試作祭りだ
お前らも来い！
You guys come too!
Sure!
（佐藤）おう！
やってやるぞ コラァ！
Let's do this!
（丸井）おおっ また僕の部屋か…
（青木･佐藤）お～！
Not my room again!
You too, Ibusaki!
（青木）伊武崎も早く来い！
You're not going to go with them, Ibusaki-kun?
行かないのかい？　伊武崎君
あっ　もしかして
女子のほうに混ざりたいのかな？
Oh, maybe you want to join the girls?
You're a closet perv, I see.
ムッツリだな 伊武崎君は
Well, there's no huge rush, though.
まあ そんなに
慌てることもないけど
Either way, first-years in our high school division can only relax for a short while.
（汐見）どっちみち高等部の１年が
のんびりしていられるのは―
今だけだからね
Why's that?
（創真）今だけって？
（黒木場）どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?
Soon, you'll be tossed outside the academy.
もうすぐ君たちは学園の外に
放り出されちゃうってこと
（黒木場）ああ？
（汐見）始まるんだよ
It's going to start.
The practical training program: the Stagiaire.
（汐見）実地研修プログラム
“スタジエール”が
The Stagiaire?
スタジエール？
NEXT TIME
THE STAGIAIRE
Next time, "The Stagiaire."